<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Muay Thai Blog</title>
    <link>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Muay Thai Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>v.networks@posteo.de (V)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>v.networks@posteo.de (V)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Inability to Stand Still</title>
      <link>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/post/2024-04-21-vom-unvermoegen-stehen-zu-bleiben/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>v.networks@posteo.de (V)</author>
      <guid>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/post/2024-04-21-vom-unvermoegen-stehen-zu-bleiben/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been the strongest guy. I’ve often heard remarks from friends, relatives, and even strangers like, “You should eat more!” or “You wimp!” along with some other, more vulgar descriptions. On top of that, I stuttered. So, I was a frail, quiet type who internalized early on that something was wrong with me and that I didn’t fit the image of what a man should be. “Masculinity” isn’t just defined by physical attributes, of course. Still, when the outside world continually signals that there’s something wrong with your body, that you’re too quiet, that you should behave or look differently, and that your shortcomings are constantly highlighted—this takes a toll.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity</title>
      <link>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/post/2023-08-30-identitaet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>v.networks@posteo.de (V)</author>
      <guid>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/post/2023-08-30-identitaet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I started Muay Thai in January 2022, I have allowed this sport to become a very strong part of my identity. On one hand, it had its benefits: it fulfilled me, brought me joy, and showed me that there is much more within me than I would have thought—both physically and mentally. On the other hand, however, it raised an entirely new problem:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What should I do when external circumstances forced me to pause the sport? Who was I then?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Preparation</title>
      <link>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/post/2023-02-23-checkliste/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>v.networks@posteo.de (V)</author>
      <guid>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/post/2023-02-23-checkliste/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like I overthought things before my first training session, many out there are probably struggling with the same question: How fit should I be before training Muay Thai for the first time? The basic thought seems logical and reasonable: If I’ve spent X weeks, months, or maybe years preparing with sports Y or Z, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have any worries. Right?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That’s why I came up with the idea of creating a sort of checklist to guide people. After all, the first training session should be perfect. So here’s a list of things you should definitely do before trying Muay Thai for the first time:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro: A is for Anxiety</title>
      <link>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/post/2023-02-1-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>v.networks@posteo.de (V)</author>
      <guid>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/post/2023-02-1-intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back then, I wasn’t necessarily aiming to learn Muay Thai, or Thai boxing, but Krav Maga. Before Krav Maga, I was fascinated by Karate for a while, and before that – I must have been 11 or 12 years old – I tried an Aikido trial lesson with my best friend at the time. I quickly realized that Aikido had little in common with &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; martial arts; it was more of a passive art and philosophy in itself, which left me feeling unfulfilled. If we go back another year or two, I found myself on a judo mat after being persuaded by another friend, but this style didn&amp;rsquo;t resonate with me either: I still remember how dizzy I would get doing somersaults during the warm-up, and how uncomfortable it felt to wrestle rather than exchange cool punches or kicks like I sometimes saw on TV.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>v.networks@posteo.de (V)</author>
      <guid>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/page/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog! Here, I write about my experiences in Muay Thai training. This includes training experiences, insights, techniques, tips &amp;amp; tricks, and much more. All information is, of course, provided without guarantee and is based solely on personal experiences. ;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have just over two years of experience, so I’m still relatively new to it—but perhaps because of that, it fulfills me to such an extent that I decided to combine two of my hobbies: Muay Thai and writing. The result is the blog you’re currently reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>v.networks@posteo.de (V)</author>
      <guid>http://muay-thai-meditationen.net/en/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to send me a message, feel free to do so via email: &lt;strong&gt;v[dot]networks[at]posteo[dot]de&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can find an icon with my email address and social media profiles in the footer below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
